The animals had their breakfast, and then Snowball and Napoleon called them together again.
>> Comrades, it is half past six, and we have a long day before us.
Today, we begin the hay harvest, but there is another matter that must be attended to first.
>> The pigs now revealed that during the past 3 months, they had taught
themselves to read and write from an old spelling book which had belonged to Mr.
Jones's children and which had been thrown on the rubbish heap.
Napoleon sent for pots of black and white paint and led the way down to the
five-barred gate that gave onto the main road.
Then Snowball, for it was Snowball who was best at writing,
took a brush between the two knuckles of his trotter, painted out Manor Farm from the top bar
of the gate, and in its place painted Animal Farm.
This was to be the name of the farm from now onwards.
After this, they went back to the farm buildings, where Snowball and Napoleon
sent for a ladder, which they caused to be set against the end wall of the big barn.
They explained that by their studies of the past 3 months, the pigs had
succeeded in reducing the principles of animalism to seven commandments.
These seven commandments would now be inscribed on the wall.
They would form an unalterable law by which all the animals on Animal Farm
must live forever after.
With some difficulty, for it is not easy for a pig to balance himself on a ladder,
Snowball climbed up and set to work, with Squealer a few rungs below him holding the paint pot.
The commandments were written on the tarred wall in great [clears throat]
white letters that could be read 30 yd away.
They ran thus: